<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on code. grind. sleep.</title>
    <link>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on code. grind. sleep.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nicolas Thauvin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Go helped for the rewrite of pg_back</title>
      <link>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2021-03-10-how-go-helped-for-the-rewrite-of-pg_back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Nicolas Thauvin</author>
      
      <guid>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2021-03-10-how-go-helped-for-the-rewrite-of-pg_back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started developping &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgrim/pg_back&#34;&gt;pg_back&lt;/a&gt;, I
wanted to keep it a simple as possible, by limiting its features. It also
limited contributions, and at some point by accepting some useful
contributions, the script grew and became not so simple. We could go on with
the shell script and try to carefully control its growth, but it will sooner or
later reach some limits of shell scripting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some time without making it evolve, I got interested in the Go
programming language. It appeared that pg_back could be a good candidate projet
to let me learn Go. This is why pg_back version 2 is written in Go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Go</title>
      <link>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2021-01-20-install-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 21:58:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Nicolas Thauvin</author>
      
      <guid>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2021-01-20-install-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Go language has been around for quite some time and one finds
more and more programs written in Go. The Go compiler and tools can be
installed using the packages of the Linux distribution, but the
easiest way to have the latest version is to use the official compiled
tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of the &lt;code&gt;golang-go&lt;/code&gt; package in Debian stable, 1.11, is too
old, so I installed the official binaries this way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development environment for Patroni</title>
      <link>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2020-12-04-patroni-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 21:23:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Nicolas Thauvin</author>
      
      <guid>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2020-12-04-patroni-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>Recently I found a missing feature in Patroni, a high availability solution for PostgreSQL written in Python.
Since I am doing more Python at work these days, I quickly made a patch. Before jumping on git push, I thought it would be nice to test if is really solves the issue. I needed a Patroni cluster, some configuration is provided and commands in the README, which is great but the instruction are not targetted toward development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2022-04-05-setup-kubernetes-on-local-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nicolas Thauvin</author>
      
      <guid>https://www.orgrim.net/en/post/2022-04-05-setup-kubernetes-on-local-vms/</guid>
      <description>;; This buffer is for text that is not saved, and for Lisp evaluation. ;; To create a file, visit it with C-x C-f and enter text in its buffer.
Install Ceph using the Ansible roles provided by ceph-ansible.
Integrate Kubernetes with Ceph to let it create persistent volume on the Ceph cluster
Once the Ceph cluster is up and running, we will use the RBD to provide block devices to the Kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
